

# Luuk Schipperheijn

Creative developer

- Rotterdam, The Netherlands
- **6** (+31) 6 499 288 28
- @ luukschipperheijn@gmail.com
- ② luuk.computer

#### Skills

#### Programming languages

JavaScript, Python, Java, C++,
SuperCollider, Max/MSP

# Frameworks / libraries / services

React, Gatsby, Node.js, Django, Android, React Native, Firebase, NGINX, Docker, Arduino, Processing, OpenFrameworks, Particle, THREE.js, Raspberry Pi

#### Other skills

Interaction design, Concept development, Music production, Photoshop, Illustrator, Ableton Live

#### Awards

#### Creative Data

Dutch Creativity Awards **2021** 

In collaboration with Fama
Volat I created the
TaxatieTruck. A driving LED
sign that shows motorists the
value of their car. Using
license plate recognition.

#### Dutch Design Award

Dutch Design Awards

# 2020

MONNIE is a digital service that aids young people in dealing with late payments. For this project, I developed a React Native app and worked on the Firebase back-end.

#### ACT Award

STRP

### 2017

MGNT, an interactive audiovisual installation that won the first STRP ACT Award for Creative Technology, showcasing its festival-worthy appeal and alignment with the Senses & Sensors theme of the STRP Biënnale.

# Languages

Dutch

English

Links

☐ <u>Portfolio</u>

in LinkedIn

GitHub

#### Summary

Creative developer with a broad range of experience encompassing front-end, back-end, and various programming languages and frameworks. Comfortable working on diverse project types, from mobile and web applications to desktop solutions, prototypes and production environments. Experienced in both solo and team settings, with a particular focus on contributing to the design process.

#### Experience

#### mot

2019 - present

Freelancer, Creative Developer

#### https://mot.studio

- Developed and maintained font-end and back-end for production level apps
- exhibitionsDeveloped physical prototypes for testing interaction in one-

Built hardware and firmware for interactive installations for

- week design sprintsDeveloped ideas and concepts for interactive installations
- Tailored proposals to address specific client needs and objectives.

### Afdeling Buitengewone Zaken

2017 - 2019

2011

Creative Developer

- https://afdelingbuitengewonezaken.nl/
  - Sole developer in a design firm, responsible for all development including websites, apps, and installations.
  - Actively participated in design thinking processes to align technical implementation with creative objectives.
  - Collaborated on prototyping and iterative design processes, providing technical insights to refine and improve design concepts
  - Applied problem-solving skills to address unexpected challenges and keep projects on track.

### vpгo 2016 - 2017

Creative Coder / Front-end Developer

### https://vpro.nl

- Collaborated with the editorial staff of <u>vpro.nl</u> to brainstorm and develop one-off interactives.
- Contributed to a large-scale project on <u>vpro.nl</u> and its spinoffs, engaging with a high volume of users daily.
- Worked within a multidisciplinary team, collaborating with front-enders, back-enders, designers, and product owners.
- Gained expertise in a complex front-end stack and contributed to back-end development.
- findings.Engaged in a Scrum-type development methodology, participating

in retrospectives and team activities.

Conducted research on optimization strategies and implemented

# Cell[0] 2014 - 2016

Founder and Developer

# https://cell-0.com

- Developed expertise in jumping into existing projects, rapidly adapting to existing codebases and providing valuable contributions to project success.
- Established and fostered a flat organizational structure collaboratively with fellow programmers, emphasizing a culture of shared responsibility, open communication, and streamlined decision-making processes.

# R&D Internship

https://steim.org/

**STEIM** 

# Collaborated on the development of both hardware and software

- components for musical instruments.Designed and implemented firmware for musical juggling balls,
  - with a specific focus on optimizing accelerometer-based trigger functionality.

# Education

STEIM / Royal 2012 - 2013 Eindhoven University 2007 - 2011
Conservatory Master of Technology Bachelor
Instruments & Industrial Design
Interfaces

Udens College 2000 - 2007
Natuur & Techniek Gymnasium